| Xiaochuan Yang, | Ph.D. |
|---|--|
| Location : Londo | n, UK Email : xiaochuan.j.yang@gmail.com LinkedIn GitHub Blog YouTube Publications |
| Summary | |
| probability theory | and accomplished Data Science Lecturer and Researcher with a Ph.D. in Mathematics. Expert ir stochastic processes, machine learning, and statistical models. Published 21 papers in reputable erences. Passionate about applying mathematical models to solve real-world problems in finance and rs. |
| Work Experience | |
| Researche | r and Lecturer in Data Science (2021-Present) Brunel University, London, UK |
| time se - Super - Publish - Organi | ng quantitative courses including Python programming, machine learning, deep learning, data analytics eries analysis, stochastic calculus, statistical models vising a Ph.D. student in the field of credit risk modelling with Hawkes processes hing in the field of stochastic modelling, statistical analysis of stochastic processes sing industrial mathematics research seminars and funding for research in the area of quantitative risk manangement |
| • EPSRC Pos | stdoctoral Researcher (2020-2021) University of Bath, UK |
| | ned papers in the area of extreme value theory and central limit theorems cted probability tail estimates for risk metrics such as VaR and shortfalls |
| • FNR Luxen | nbourg-Singapore bilateral researcher (2018-2020) |
| cesses | ned papers fundamental to risk modelling: high frequency statistics of Gaussian processe, point pro s, extreme value theory, central limit theorems Partical Differential Equations (Master's course, Univeristy of Luxembourg), crucial for financial instru pricing |
| Assistant F | Professor (2016-2018) Michigan State University, East Lansing, USA |
| | actuarial science fundamentals: probability and statistics ned papers in statistics of Gaussian processes, Levy processes, and jump diffusions |

Professional Skills

- Quantitative Risk Management Know-how:
 - Stochastic Models: GARCH, EWMA, EVT, Point Processes, diffusions, factor model...
 - Dependency Modelling: Variance-Covariance, Mixture, Copula, Self-Excitement
 Statistical Estimation of VaR, ES, EL, PD, LGD

 - Monte Carlo, Historical Simulation
 - Pricing: Stochastic Calculus, Semimartingales, PDE, QuantLib
 - Regulatory Approach: EBA guidelines, CRR, Basel III pillars, IRB, IFRS 9, IPEV guidlines
- Technical Skills:

- Advanced Python Programming; Git version control
- Proficient in R, SAS, Excel, SQL
- Mastery of Computing Libraries: numpy, numba, scipy, jax
- Analytics and Machine Learning: pandas, scikit-learn, PyTorch, XGBoost, SHAP, matplotlib, seaborn

· Research Skills

- Aquired a robust analytical mindset through 10 years of reseasrch in quantitative fields
- Critical evaluation of existing methodologies and development of original ideas for new challenges
- Ability to quickly learn any new field

Consulting Experience

- Defence Data Research Centre & Alan Turing Institute (2023) Exeter, UK
 - Topic: toxin diagonosis by cellular morphology; challenge posed by Defence Science and Technology Lab
 - Managed the entire pipeline from data processing to model validation, using tools like pandas, sklearn,
 XGBoost, PyTorch; Explained model decision with SHAP
- · NHS Rheumatology (2021) Bath, UK
 - Topic: Machine Learning for damage detection in Psoriatic Arthritis
 - Proposed physiological-based networks and clustering framework; clustered patients with similar diseases using vectorized data representation; investiaged disease progression over time

Education

- Ph.D. in Mathematics (2016) Université Paris-Est, Paris, France
 - Thesis: "Dimensional properties of regularities of jump diffusion processes"
 - Received a PhD thesis prize of \$6000 (one of 13 recipients in France that year)
 - Funded by the DIM Scholarship from the Île-de-France region
 - Jump diffuions widely used in modelling risk factors and emerging generative Al
- Master in Applied Mathematics (2013) Université Paris-Est, Paris, France
 - Courses: stochastic calculus, PDE, interest rate models, Levy processes, non-parametric statistics, limit theorems, stochastic models, signal and image processing with wavelets, Python
 - Bezout Scholarship recipient
- Bachelor in Applied Mathematics (2009) Jilin University, China (top 6 in mathematics)
 - Courses: statistics, algorithms, differential equations, numerical analysis, C programming
- French Language Training (2011) Caen, France. DALF Level C1.

Langueges

· Bilingual: English, Chinese

• Level C1: French